# Bharathi Kannan V

## **Full Stack Developer**

Experienced software professional specialising in modern web technologies, with a track record of delivering robust applications and optimizing development workflows.

bharathikannanv05@gmail.com

+919443470347

Coimbatore, India

\_

www.bharathikannan.com

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# 

03/2023 - Present

Bangalore

Roles and Responsibilities

- Frontend Lead Responsible for building accessible web applications with React, Javascript, HTML and CSS.
- Full-stack developer with a primary focus on UI development.

## **Software Engineer**

Twilio 🗷

10/2022 - 02/2023

Bangalore

Roles and Responsibilities

 Contributed to development and delivery of core services for Studio, a low-code application development platform.

#### **Technical Lead IV**

Photon Interactive

05/2020 - 10/2022

Chennai

Roles and Responsibities

- Application lead managing a team of 2 Frontend engineers and 3 QA resources.
- Architect Lead to analyse and develop POCs for upcoming features in product.

#### **PROJECTS**

Marketer Dashboard (11/2023 - Present)

- Orchestrating UI development strategies and leading a team of four developers.
- Optimised development workflow by implementing Storybook, automated UI testing, and standardised code quality tools while establishing comprehensive coding standards.
- Engineered reusable and accessible data visualisation components using Recharts, delivering complex interactive charts that garnered significant client satisfaction.

Studio - A Low Code Application Builder (10/2022 - 02/2023)

 Streamlined local development workflow, reducing UI build time and accelerating feature delivery.

Clinical Trials Web Application (05/2021 - 10/2022)

 Developed dynamic clinical forms UI with branching logic, enabling adaptive questionnaires and clinician review workflows.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Engineering**Sri Ramakrishna Engineering College

2012 - 2016 Coimbatore

Specialization

 Computer Science and Engineering

### **SKILLS**



## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Just Javascript Certification by Dan Abramov (03/2023)

The course consists of 10 modules in which we explore the Javascript universe and build our mental model from the inside. Learned about primitives of Javascript and understood how objects work under the hood.

Joy Of React Certification by Josh Comeau (03/2023) ☑

Workshop-based React course provided by Josh Comeau. Learned about best practices for developing web applications with react. Understood Component API design.

Epic React Certification from Kent C. Dodds (03/2021)

Workshop-based advanced React course provided by Kent C. Dodds and egghead.io. Learned about all the parts in web development with React from developing, styling, testing, and measuring the performance of a production application.

Front-End Web Development with React (03/2020)

Completed the course with 100% Grade provided by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology through Coursera

Certified Full Stack Engineer (03/2019)

Provided by National Institute of Information Technology and Sponsored by Cognizant Technology Solutions

# **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

An overall experience of 8 years in Web Application Development, UI Design, and Web-based technologies (04/2016 - Present)

4 years of experience in SPA development with TypeScript, React, Redux, Next JS, Amazon Web Sevices, DynamoDB, Firebase, Cloud Firestore, Apollo GraphQL, Material UI, HTML, SCSS, and CSS. (03/2019 - Present)

Exploring trending technologies and tools like RSC, Remix, Next JS, Chakra UI, Recharts, CSS-In-JS and Interested in contributing to Open-source tools, and Writing blogs.

#### INTERESTS

Phones Tech Blog Open Source